## **Personal Info**

Syahir bin Shahrul No 20 Jalan TJ 8/5, Taman Temerloh Jaya, 28000 Temerloh, Pahang

<u>syahir6530@gmail.com</u> 0145440948



## **Objective**

Offers my skills and know how in the technical skills to the company whilst improving and enhancing my experience and knowledge from another view given problems and also improve my problem solving and troubleshooting skills for future benefits.

## **Working Experience**

Strateq System Sdn Bhd		
Location	Temerloh, Pahang	
Duration of work	April 2016 – June 2016	
Company Background	<ul> <li>Company that are subsidiaries in maintenance, troubleshoot of personal computers, notebooks, servers and database</li> </ul>	
Position	Field Engineer	
Job Scope	<ul> <li>Maintenance, cleaning and troubleshoot of personal computers and notebooks</li> </ul>	
	Hitachi-LG Data Storage Sdn Bhd	
Location	Bangi, Selangor	
Duration of work	Dec 2013 – April 2014	
Company Background	<ul> <li>Joint venture between Hitachi and LG</li> <li>Product manufactured includes DVD and Blu- Ray drives for desktop and notebook computers</li> </ul>	
Position	Practical Trainee	
Job Scope	<ul> <li>Assigned to Production Engineering Department</li> <li>Assist the technician in maintenance of machine and tools</li> <li>Machine maintained includes drive test and drive programming</li> </ul>	

# **Education**

Universiti Malaysia Pahang		
Location	Gambang, Pahang	
Duration	Sep 2015 – Feb 2018	
Course	Bachelor Of Engineering Technology in Electrical (Hons)	
Latest CGPA	3.56	
German-Malaysian Institute		
Location	Kajang, Selangor	
Duration	Jan 2012 – Dec 2014	
Course	Diploma of Industrial Electronics Majored In Mechatronics	
Latest CGPA	3.47	
Projects	Styrofoam Recycle Machine(FYP)	
	<ul> <li>Machine that recycles Styrofoam into small pots for flower</li> </ul>	
	<ul><li>PLC as main controller ( Siemens S7-200 )</li></ul>	
	<ul> <li>Actuator includes Single Phase Induction Motor and Electro Pneumatics System</li> </ul>	
Sekolah Menengah Teknik Bentong		
Location	Bentong, Pahang	
Duration	2006 – 2007	
Course	Mechanical Engineering	
SPM Result	Passed all subject	

# **Achievement**

Dean's List at GMI	Sem 1(Jan 2012), Sem 2(Jul 2012)
	Sem 3(Jan 2013), Sem 4(Jul 2013)
	Sem 5(Jan 2014)
Engaged in IPMA Race at Malacca	2013
Involved in GMI's Public Speaking	2012
Appointed as school librarian	2003 – 2007
Joint leadership seminar	2005
Involved in Choral Speaking Competition	2003

## **Technical Skills**

Hydraulics and Pneumatics	Able to install the pneumatics and hydraulics system
Basic Metal Work	<ul> <li>Involved in sheet metal forming</li> </ul>
Basic turning and milling	<ul> <li>Able to use milling and turning machine</li> </ul>
Microsoft Office	■ Microsoft Excel 2016
	<ul><li>Microsoft Word 2016</li></ul>
	<ul> <li>Microsoft PowerPoint 2016</li> </ul>
2D and 3D Design and Drafting	<ul> <li>Autodesk Autocad 2012</li> </ul>
Software	■ Solidworks 2012/2013
	<ul> <li>Adobe Photoshop CS5/CC</li> </ul>
Operating System	<ul><li>From Windows XP to Windows 8</li></ul>
	<ul><li>Including fresh OS install</li></ul>
	<ul> <li>Able to assemble the PC</li> </ul>
PLC Programming	<ul> <li>Programmable Logic Controller</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Usually used in industry as a controller from simple to complex</li> </ul>
	process
	<ul> <li>Ladder diagram as programming language</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>PLC Programmed includes Siemens S7-200 and S7-300</li> </ul>

## **Language Skills**

Language	Condition
Bahasa Melayu	Excellent
English Language	Good

### References

Ms Jamilah Mohd Ali Ms Safrina Zainal Abidin Head of Department, Head Of Section, Registrar/Student Affairs, Learning Resources, German-Malaysian Institute, German-Malaysian Institute, Jalan Ilmiah, Taman Universiti, Jalan Ilmiah, Taman Universiti, 43000 Kajang, Selangor 43000 Kajang, Selangor 03 - 8921 9308 013 - 258 5628 jamilah@gmi.edu.my szagmi@hotmail.com



Universiti Malaysia Pahang Lebuhraya Tun Razak, 26300 Gambang Kuantan, Pahang Darul Makmur Tet: +609-549 2750 | Faka/Fax: +609-549 2525

#### Jabatan Jaringan Industri & Masyarakat (JJIM)

Industry Partnership & Community Relation Department

### UMP.30.02/ 13.16/ 06 (TB15066-10)

18/03/2017

#### TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN

#### LETTER OF VERIFICATION

NAME : SYAHIR BIN SHAHRUL

STUDENT ID : TB15066

PROGAMME : SARJANA MUDA TEKNOLOGI KEJURUTERAAN (ELEKTRIKAL) DENGAN KEPUJIAN

FACULTY : FAKULTI TEKNOLOGI KEJURUTERAAN

I hereby declare that that the student/s stated as above is our year 2 student of Universiti Malaysia Pahang, Kuantan, Malaysia.

This is to inform that he/she will undergo an Industrial Training program starting from 04/09/2017 to 16/02/2018.

Should your company offer a placement to our student(s), a confirmation of acceptance letter would be sent to you by our student(s). The University will only send a Confirmation for Placement letter to the student's selected company.

It is enclosed in Income Tax Act 1967 that companies which offered placement for universities students who undergo their industrial traning eligible for Double Deduction Taxation Incentive. For more information, please visit our website at <a href="http://jim.ump.edu.my/taxdeduction">http://jim.ump.edu.my/taxdeduction</a>

### "BERKHIDMAT UNTUK NEGARA"

Regards,



DR. MOHD ZAMRI BIN IBRAHIM

Deputy Director

Career Placement & Development Centre (CPDC)
Industry Partnership & Community Relation Department

Universiti Malaysia Pahang

Tel : 09-549 2750 Faks : 09-549 2525 e-mail : li@ump.edu.my